Joseph Chung

5009 – 5 Buttermill Ave Vaughan ON L4K 0J5 416-678-4920 yj.chung@mail.utoronto.ca

Professional Profile

Emerging research analyst. Researcher. Experimenter. Skilled at data mining to extract semantic information from raw data. Focused on data analytics. Expert at analyzing and summarizing data to present them in charts, graphs, and tables, making complex data easy to read and understand. Driven by a desire to learn and apply that knowledge to solve problems.

Education

Bachelor of Information

2024

Faculty of Information, the University of Toronto

(expected)

Information studies (2022 – 2024)

Mathematical Statistics (2018 – 2022)

Representative Courses: Information in Organizations, Information Policy in Canadian and Global Contexts, User Experience Research, Mathematical Statistics, Regression Modelling, Survey Sampling, Computational Reasoning, Data Analytics

Selected Projects

2021 Station Assessment: Industrial Safety

2021

Ontario Power Generation, Darlington

- Led data collection of 3000 incident reports related to the Health & Safety of the workers; prepared regulations and policy analysis reports based on the findings
- Reassessed reports from previous years to rectify policy development
- Reviewed and tabulated safety briefings to identify any weaknesses in the reporting system and refined the assessment to address these weaknesses
- Conducted survey sampling, interviewed 1400 workers to gather data and analyzed the effectiveness of current policy in safety procedures across the station

Professional Experience

Research Analyst 2019 – 2021

Ontario Power Generation, Darlington

- Solicited advice from committees involved in policy development and program design to assess current safety policy
- Supported the execution of strategic initiatives in collaboration with internal and external stakeholders
- Decomposed business requirements and translated them into design specifications
- Extracted and analyzed data to generate insights and recommendations

Process and Control Research Assistant

2016 - 2018

Blue Water Research Center, Sarnia

- Supported day-to-day operational processes, developing management activities and implementing administrative tasks to achieve research results
- Conducted independent analysis and assessment to resolve strategic issues
- Designed and produced regular and ad-hoc reports and dashboards

Certifications

 Certification of Virtual Engagement Program at Risk & Insurance Center and Royal Bank of Canada

Skills and Qualifications

Data visualization MS Office Suite Korean (Native)

Data modelling R Adult Safe Hockey League

Survey sampling Python

Hypothesis testing Power BI

Data mining SQL

Machine learning C++ (novice)